Josue Cedeno

Fort Worth, TX, 76102 | (917) 664-6672

josuecedeno@yahoo.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/josuecedeno/

Frontend Web Developer seeking remote and local opportunities. Recent full stack bootcamp graduate with exposure to HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, React Native, and Node JS. Self-motivated problem solver looking to drive technical projects from design, implementation, deployment, and monitoring. In addition to coding, I have 20+ years of analytics, training, and management experience. Contract or full time. Github: https://github.com/mister-josuecedeno

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer Jan 2021 - Present

Chingu, Fort Worth, TX (Remote)

- Work side-by-side with a five-person remote team building financial literacy tools with a focus on branding, web design, and user experience
- As the team is 100% remote, there is a strong reliance on my excellent written and verbal communication skills for consistency in meeting deadlines
- Our current project is a mortgage calculator built with HTML, CSS, and Javascript. My role is web design, branding, and user experience.

WordPress Developer Mar 2019 - Present

City Life Church, Fort Worth, TX

- Work collaboratively with the team to design, build, and maintain features to extend the site functionality to support special projects
- Install and maintain WordPress plugins to provide members direct access to multiple video portals and improve the user experience

Business Intelligence Analyst May 2001 - Mar 2019

Citigroup, New York, NY

- Partnered with developers to help build understanding, design, problem solve, document, test, and train for business application builds
- Built profitability database models used by senior management to support business relationships with thousands of Citi's top clients, as well as internal stakeholders
- Provided analysis and reporting, using tools like Tableau, to help senior management understand current status and trends for planning and client conversations
- Communicated regularly with stakeholders to provide project and analysis updates

EDUCATION

Full Stack and Mobile Development Jun 2020 - Nov 2020

Nucamp Full Stack Bootcamp, Fort Worth, TX

Educated in the MERN stack for front end and back end development (Mongo Db, Express, React, Node JS), as well as HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Git, and React Native.

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.) - Marketing Sep 1989 - May 1993

Iona College, NY

Graduated Magna Cum Laude with Honors

SKILLS

Intermediate in: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Tableau, Web Development, User Experience

Basic in: React, React Native, Node JS, Express, Mongo Db, Sass, JQuery, Server-side